A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Audiovisual materials, Series 39 FA756
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, Political Video material, 1960-1975; 2
  - 1966
    - Governor Rockefeller - Public Service Announcement: Vote - Take 2 and Take 3, c. 1966; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 17, Reel AV 11488)
      Governor Rockefeller speaking to the public about voter registration.
    - Jacob J. Javits Questions and Answers - Take 5, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1966 September 30; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 17, Reel AV 11483)
    - Personal Medicaid - Take 34 (Without NAR), Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1966 September 20; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 15, Reel AV 11463)
    - State University of New York - Take 6, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1966 October 07; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute; 2 inch videotape (Box 15, Reel AV 11464)
    - Medicaid - Take 48, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1966 September 20; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 15, Reel AV 11470)
    - Phoney Taxes - Take 15 (unedited, medium shot), Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1966 October 28; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 16, Reel AV 11474)
  - 1967
    - Inauguration 1967, Assembly Room Speeches, 1967 January 2; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 30, Reel AV 10604)
      From the Capitol Building in Albany, the inaugeration of Nelson A. Rockefeller in his third term as Governor of New York state.
    - The Governor's Annual Message to the Legislature, 1967 January 4; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 59, Reel AV 10620)
      Governor Nelson Rockefeller addresses the opening session of the 1967 New York state legislature, also known as the State of the State Message.
    - Gun Shop: Rockefeller for President, 1967 June 5; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 9, Reel AV 11407)
  - 1968
    - Nelson and Winthrop Rockefeller Nominating Segments, 1968 August; Sound, Color, 51 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 66, Reel AV 10626)
      From the 1968 Republican National Convention, Gerald Ford introduces Governor Raymond P. Shafer who nominates Nelson A. Rockefeller for Republican candidate for President. Rockefeller speaks. Also speaking: Winthrop Rockefeller, and others.
      Program has intermittent sections where picture goes to black.
    - Rockefeller Video Tape Spots - Campaign Trail, 1968 August 6; Sound, Color, 36 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 43, Reel AV 10632)
    - Rockefeller Video Tape Spots, Sound, Color, Black and white, 28 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 39, Reel AV 10628)
    - Rockefeller - The Man Who Can, 1968 July 16; Sound, Color, 60 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 42, Reel AV 10631)
      Film documenting Nelson A. Rockefeller's 1968 run for President. Program aired on NBC-TV.
      16mm film print available: AV 1815
    - Governor Nelson Rockefeller's Declaration of Non-Candidacy in the 1968 Primaries, Sound, Color, 35 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 41, Reel AV 10630)
      Begins with one minute of color bars and tones.
      Press conference with Nelson Rockefeller reiterating that he is not a candidate campaigning directly or indirectly for the presidency of the United States.
    - Seconding Speeches at Republican National Convention, 1968 August; Sound, Color, 24 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 51, Reel AV 10640)
      Gerald Ford announces various politicians who give seconding speeches for the nomination of Nelson Rockefeller to be the Republican presidential candidate.
    - 1968 Campaign Spots: Two Americas, Sound, Black and white, 1 minute; 2 inch videotape (Box 4, Reel AV 10673)
    - Rockefeller: The Presidential Man (from The Man Who Can) - Segment One, 1968 June 10; Sound, Color, 7 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 21, Reel AV 11405)
    - Rockefeller: The Presidential Man (from The Man Who Can) - Segment Three, 1968; Sound, Color, 16 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 18, Reel AV 11496)
    - Moon: Rockefeller for President, 1968 June 17; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 12, Reel AV 11442)
    - Ohio: Rockefeller For President, 1968 July 11; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 16, Reel AV 11481)
  - 1969
    - Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller Message to the Legislature, 1969 January 8; Sound, Color, 47 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 54, Reel AV 10615)
      Tape begins with 1 minute of color bars and tones, followed by approximately 17 minutes of unedited footage from the Assemby Chamber in the New York state capitol building.
      Governor Rockefeller presents his annual message to the New York Legislature. This is his eleventh such appearance.
    - Breakfast with the Long Island Association, 1969 August 7; Sound, Black and white, 102 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 55, Reel AV 10616)
      From Georgian Room of the Garden City Hotel, Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller speaks to members of the Long Island Association of Commerce and Industry about the Long Island Railroad.
    - Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot to Vote "Yes" for N.Y.S. Constitutional Amendments, 1969 October 29; Sound, Color, 105 seconds; 2 inch videotape (Box 10, Reel AV 11415)
    - NAR on the Eddie Meath Show, 1969 January 16; Sound, Color, 15 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 16, Reel AV 11478)
  - 1970
    - Campaign Message, 1970 October 23; Sound, Color, 5 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 1, Reel AV 10646)
      Begins with 50 seconds of color bars and tones.
      A message from Nelson Rockefeller on the upcoming election. He claims Arthur J. Goldberg is running a campaign of untruths and underhanded tactics.
    - Governor Rockefeller - State of the State Address, 1970 January 8; 2 inch videotape; Sound, Color, 32 minutes (Box 67, Reel AV 10641)
      Annual message from the governor.
    - Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spots Compilation (20 and 30 seconds), 1970; Sound, Color, 16 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 20, Reel AV 11517)
    - Governor Rockefeller Run for Re-election Acceptance Speech - Spot 2 (and Spot 1), 1970 April 6; Sound, Color, 4 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 18, Reel AV 11499)
    - Economy, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 13; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 9, Reel AV 11413)
    - Goods on Credit - Public Service Announcement, NYS Department of Commerce, 1970 October 6; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 9, Reel AV 11414)
    - Sailboat, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 6; Sound, Color, 1 minute; 2 inch videotape (Box 11, Reel AV 11427)
      Begins with 40 seconds of bars and tones.
    - Ignorance, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 19; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 11, Reel AV 11428)
    - Mental Health, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 1; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 11, Reel AV 11433)
    - Excerpts of Meeting Between Governor Rockefeller and Labor Leaders, 1970 October 27; Sound, Color, 6 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 12, Reel AV 11436)
      Governor Rockefeller speaks about the economy, job growth, crime, education, drugs, and senior citizens.
    - Vincent Impellitteri Re-election Spot for NAR (10 second version), 1970 October 13; Sound, Color, 1 minute; 2 inch videotape (Box 12, Reel AV 11441)
    - Endorsement: Unidentified Man Endorses Nelson A. Rockefeller, circa 1970; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 13, Reel AV 11444)
    - Governor Rockefeller Answers Questions on Pollution and His Plans For the Next Four Years, 1970 September 29?; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 13, Reel AV 11445)
    - Clean Streets, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 13; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 13, Reel AV 11447)
    - Voting Record, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 19; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 13, Reel AV 11449)
    - Endorsement: Judge Samuel Liebowitz Endorses Nelson A. Rockefeller: "Law & Order", 1970 October 21; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 13, Reel AV 11450)
      Endorsement spot from Democrats For Rockefeller.
    - Pay Envelope, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 13; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 17, Reel AV 11484)
    - Endorsement: Jacob J. Javits Endorses Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1970 September 24?; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 14, Reel AV 11460)
      Senator Jacob J. Javits endorses Nelson A. Rockefeller for re-election as New York State governor.
    - Endorsement: Assemblyman Ramos Endorses Nelson A. Rockefeller - #6, 1970 October 12; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 14, Reel AV 11459)
    - Higher Education, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 6; Sound, Color, 1 minute; 2 inch videotape (Box 15, Reel AV 11466)
    - Drugs Rebuttal, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 13; Sound, Color, 2 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 15, Reel AV 11467)
    - Governor Rockefeller Budget Message Spots, 1970 January 16; Sound, Color, 9 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 15, Reel AV 11471)
      Compilation reel with Governor Rockefeller discussing various issues, including education, human well-being, and the environment.
    - Vincent Impellitteri Re-election Spot for NAR (30 second version), 1970 October 13; Sound, Color, 1 minute; 2 inch videotape (Box 15, Reel AV 11472)
    - Governor Rockefeller Run For Re-election Acceptance Speech - Spot 1, 1970 April 6; Sound, Color, 4 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 16, Reel AV 11475)
    - Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spots Compilation (30 seconds), 1970; Sound, Color, 17 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 16, Reel AV 11477)
    - Question #8, Governor Rockefeller Campaign Spot, 1970 October 19; Sound, Color, 1 minute; 2 inch videotape (Box 16, Reel AV 11479)
  - 1971-1975
    - Governor Nelson Rockefeller's Special News Conference on Narcotics, 1973 January 22; Sound, Color, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 31, Reel AV 10605)
      Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller's press conference in Albany, New York regarding the drug problem in New York state. Speakers include: Reverend Oberia D. Dempsey, Reverend Earl B. Moore, Glester Hinds, Dr. George W. McMurray, and Dr. Robert W. Baird. A question and answer session with the press concludes the program.
      The video begins with 40 seconds of color bars and tones.
    - Senator's Report, 1975 February 25; Sound, Color, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 56, Reel AV 10617)
      From Washington, a report to Pennsylvania from the U.S. Senate by Senator Hugh Scott. Scott answers questions from his three guests from the press.
    - Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller Press Conference: Resignation as Governor of New York, 1973 December 11; Sound, Color, 35 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 57, Reel AV 10618)
      Excerpts from a press conference where Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller discusses his resignation as New York state governor. Event takes place in the Red Room of the state capital.
    - Governor Nelson Rockefeller: Appearance on the Today Show - Discussing New York State Drug Laws, 1973 September 7; Sound, Color, 17 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 58, Reel AV 10619)
      Governor Rockefeller's appearance on the Today Show where he discusses newly implemented drugs laws with host Barbara Walters.
    - Scenes of Kykuit, c.1970s; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Box 6, Reel AV 10688)
      Begins with color bars and tones. Program begins at 1:30. Heavy image distortion from 4:45 - 7:15.
      Exterior and interior footage of Kyikuit, a 40-room house in Westchester County, New York, built by John D. Rockefeller.
    - Nelson Rockefeller on The David Frost Show: Episode 524, 1971 July 20; Sound, Color, 90 minutes (Box 1, Reel AV 11564)
      Interview program. Includes original promotional spots.